# **Charles Wu**

**UX** Designer & Developer

1-647-767-6126

charleswu.ca 🖵

hi@charleswu.ca ≥

# **Summary**

A versatile user-experience designer & developer. Adept in converting user needs into product requirements, with project analysis skills. Efficient at creating designs that translate into tangible results, through the means of prototypes, animation, and code.

# **Experience**

# Senior UX Designer

Sep 2016 - Apr 2018

CareerJSM, Toronto

- Designed features, wireframes, mockups, and prototypes for stakeholders to demonstrate new features
- Conducted user testing and interviews for product validation and quality assurance
- Audited and implemented code for accessibility, responsiveness, and localization
- Presented to and mentored coworkers on UX best practices

#### **UX** Designer

Aug 2015 - Jul 2016

#### **DIVE Networks, Toronto**

- Led company UX training sessions to enhance overall product direction
- Optimized content for web and TV displays, factoring in content size, speed, and viewer distance
- Created user personas and use-cases to enhance functionality and usability for key audiences
- Developed an automation script to isolate anomalies by analyzing visual differences

### **UX** Designer

Jan 2015 - Jun 2015

Crowd Curio, Waterloo

- Improved user engagement by testing and optimizing different layouts and through added gamification elements
- Designed information architecture maps, wireframes, and prototypes, implemented with HTML/CSS/JS

#### **UX** Designer

Jun 2014 - Aug 2014

McKinsey Digital Labs, New York

- Produced wireframes, storyboards, and mock-ups, making use of user research and user-centered design principles
- Developed and presented interactive prototypes with FramerJS

### iOS Developer & Product Designer

Jan 2013 - Apr 2013

AlphaBroder (formerly Ash City), Richmond Hill

- Independently managed, designed, and developed a mobile app, from conception to delivery, within a 4 month deadline
- Organized and led user testing sessions

### Skills

**UX:** User Research, User Testing, Wireframing, Information Architecture Design, Prototyping (Adobe CS, Sketch, Axure), Web Accessibility (WCAG 2.0)

**Dev:** HTML, CSS (SCSS, BEM), JS (Vanilla, Ember), Python, Git

### Education

Bachelors of Applied Science (BASc), University of Waterloo

2010 - 2015

Systems Design Engineering, Option in Management Science

# **Projects and Interests**

#### **Projects**

- Curio-X: Designed and optimized a citizen science and gamification project to digitally catalog plant images
- BufferBox (acquired by Google): Led a team of 3 student designers and marketers for product growth
- Proxima: Fabricated a glove to wirelessly transfer data via gestures
- Focus: Built and published a study tool
- InFit: Developed a fitness tracking app to process biometric data

#### Recreation

In my free time, I enjoy rock climbing, photography, volleyball, biking, cooking, and traveling.